Guide to the James E. Jackson and Esther Cooper Jackson Papers TAM 347
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
- Series XI: Southern Negro Youth Congress.
  - The Southern Hate Press: A Threat to Post-War Democracy by Esther Cooper, ca.1944 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Series XII: Speeches.
  - Subseries XII:A: Alphabetical Order.
    - Birmingham, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Black Struggle, Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Capitalism, Undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - China, Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Communist Party (Programs), Undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Communist Party (Workshops), 1982, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - A Communist View of the Nation's Need - Speech, Q&A, Press Conference at Oberlin College, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Disarmament, Undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Excerpts, Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Funerals / Memorial Services, Undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Greeting on the Birthday of Gus Hall, 1980 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Greetings on the Birthday of Simon Gerson / Speakers' Intro, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Greetings to Communist Parties (GDR, Bulgarian, French, Canadian, CPSU, Polish), Undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Ho Chi-Minh - Leninist, Undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Marxism-Leninism, Undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Middle East, Undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Peace, Undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - On Publication of Soviet Books, Speech at Progress Publishers, Undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - On Receiving the Joliot-Curie Gold Medal for Peace, Undated (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - South, Undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Soviet Union, Undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Speeches Translated into Foreign Languages, Undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - U.S. Policy, Undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Vietnam, Undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - World Peace Council, Undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Subseries XII:B: Chronological Order.
    - Outline for Speech on the 29th Anniversary of Soviet Union, Los Angeles, State Committee, C.P., 1946 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Statement Before Open Hearing of House Judiciary Committee on Callahan Bill, Lansing, Michigan, May 1947 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Speeches, 1950-1959 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Speeches, 1960-1968 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Speeches, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Speeches, 1974-1978 (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Speeches, 1979-1982 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, 1983-2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Series XIII: Subject Files.
  - 19th All-Union Party Conference, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Addis Ababa, Conference, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Ad Hoc Bulletin(Inner Party Bulletin prepared by the Ad Hoc Committee for a Scientific Socialist Line), 1963, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - African-American Civil Right Movement, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - African-American Clergy Caucus, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - African-American Equality Committee, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - African-American Equality Conference, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - African-American Summit, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - African Freedom, Support for - National Conference, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - African National Congress, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - African Research Group, Boston, Mass., Undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Afro-Asian Caribbean Organisation, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Afro-Asian Peoples' Solidarity Organization (AAPSO), 1979 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Afro Scholar Newsletter, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Alabama State Conference of Negro Veterans, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - American Dilemma Study Material, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - American Dilemma Study Material 2, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18A)
  - Angola, 1981, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Anonymous Notes on the Party, Undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Anti-Monopoly Committee, Undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Anti-War Strike News, Apr 1937 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Arctic Rim Peace Conference, Undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Army Air Force Segregation, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Army Talk Orientation, Fact Sheet 64 - Fascism, Mar 24 1945 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Assessments of Developments in Socialism - Panel on Socialism, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - The Bakke Case, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Black Belt (Data), Undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Black Draft Counselling Union, Undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Black Panther Party, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Black Radical Congress, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Book Covers, Undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Border Dispute Between India and China (Debate Transcript) - Jackson presents the position of Red China, Undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Brooklyn Youth Conference, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Brown, Roberts - in Poppy's Notes ( Amsterdam News), 1966 (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - Burma, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Burnham, Dorothy Challenor, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Burnham, Louis, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - Burroughs, Nannie, Undated (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Campaign for A People's Peace Treaty, Undated (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - Chicago Chapter Coalition of Black Trade Unionists, Undated (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - The Chicago Plan to Increase the Power of Negro Voters, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - Chile, 1965-1975 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - City of New Orleans vs. Walter Green (Jackson Testimony), 17120 (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - Civil Right Congress, 1949 (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - Committees of Correspondence, 1993, 1997, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - Committees of Correspondence, California, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - Communist Party Congress in Budapest, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - Communists in Harlem During the Depression- reviewed by Paul Berman, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Communist and Workers Parties, Consultative Meeting (Moscow, Vietnam), 1965 (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - Congressional Black Caucus, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - Council on African Affairs, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - Course Materials - Classes Attended/Taught by Jackson (C.P./Workers School), 1936, 1937, 1956-1957 (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - Crockett, George, 1949, 1970-1974 (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Cuba, 1968, 1980, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Cuba / Fidel Castro, 1965, 1968, 1979 (Box 13, Folder 56)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 57)
  - Davis, Angela, 1970-1971 (Box 13, Folder 58)
  - Davis, Angela - Memo Written By Henry Winston, Undated (Box 13, Folder 59)
  - The Daily World, Undated (Box 13, Folder 60)
  - Defend Negro Leadership, National Committee to, 1950-1954 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Defend Our Civil Rights by Judge Hubert T. Delany, 1952 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Detroit Red Squad (FOIA File), 1947-1972 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Discussion Bulletin on Little Rock and Negro Peoples Struggle for Freedom: Educational Dept., CPUSA, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Dolson, Jim, Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Duberman's Biography of Paul Robeson - Another Comment, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B. - articles about, 1946-1995 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B. - Centennial at Carnegie Hall, Feb 1968 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B. - Clippings, 1946-1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B. - Interview on Channel 5, Jun 1957 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B. - Memorial Center (Ghana), 1986 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B. - Testimony, Undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Du Bois - Foster School of Marxism-Leninism, 1973-1977 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Du Bois - Foster School of Marxism-Leninism / Evaluations, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Economic Research Materials, Undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Equal Rights Party, 1872 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Fact Sheets on Institutional Racism, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Fast, Howard, Undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - France, Undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Gellért, Hugo, 1975, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Glasnost - A Chronology of the Gorbachev Era, ca.1988-1989 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Goddard Collage, Third World Program, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Grenada, 1981-1984 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Guyana, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Harrington, Ollie, 1976, 1977, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Harrington, Ollie Drawings - photocopies., Undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Harrington, Ollie Drawings - photocopies., 1955-1979 (Box 14, Folder 26A)
  - Harrington, Ollie Drawings - photocopies., 1980-1981 (Box 14, Folder 26B)
  - Harrington, Ollie Drawings (Bootsie and others) - photocopies., Undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Hastie, William Circuit Judge - Dissenting Opinion, Nelson, Steve v. United States of America, 1954 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Hemispheric Conference / Meyerson, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Henderson, Joseph P. (Tribute to), 1990 (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Henry Winston Memorial Committee, 1986-1987 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Howard University Student Activism (United Student Peace Committee, etc.), 1932-1940 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Hudson, Hosea, 1971, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - India, Undated (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Indonesia (Action Conference), ca.1945-1947 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - International Emergency Conference in Support of Vietnam, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - International Negro Youth Council (Committee), Undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - International Union, United Automobile, Aerospace and Agricultural Implement Workers of America (UAW), 1979 (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Isthmian Youth Congress, Undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Jackson, Jesse, 1984-1992 (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - The Jeanette Rankin Brigade - "A Call to American Women", 1967 (Box 14, Folder 41)
  - Jewish Affairs, 1981, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - Jones, Corporal, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - The KAL Incident, South Korea, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - King's Dream Society, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 45)
  - Labor Youth League, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Latin-America, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - League of Black Workers, ca.1970 (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Lenin Self-Study Series 1. - Elements of Marxist-Leninist Theory, Undated (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Levine's Testimony on Jackson, Undated (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - Lightfoot, Claude, Undated (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - List of the Twelve National Unions Organized Between 1860-1866, Undated (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Malcolm X; Organization of Afro-American Unity, 1964 (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Marxist Institutes, 1956-1978 (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Marxist-Leninist Quotations Collected by Jackson, Undated (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - Black Liberation Journal: A Marxist Quarterly Review of the Negro Liberation Struggle[National Black Liberation Commission of the Communist Party, U.S.A.], Undated (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - McCarran Act, ca.1950s (Box 14, Folder 57)
  - McKie, Bill, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 58)
  - Mesaba Park Student Evaluations, Undated (Box 14, Folder 59)
  - A Monthly Journal of Negro Thought and Opinion (prospectus), Undated (Box 14, Folder 60)
  - The Muskie Debate, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 61)
  - National Alliance Against Racist and Political Repression, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 62)
  - National Americanism Commission, 1959 (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - National Anti-Imperialist Conference - a Call, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 64)
  - National Black Coalition, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Captive Nations Committee, Undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, Undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - National Committee of Negro Churchmen, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (N.A.A.C.P.), 1957, 1958, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - National Caucus of Labor Committees, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - National Negro Congress, Undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - National Negro Labor Council, Undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - National Student Committee Meeting, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - National Student Federation of China, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - National Student League, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - National Student Strike for Peace, Undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Negro-American Labor Council, ca.1966 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Negro and Negro Youth Problems (Conference on), 1939 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Negro Liberation / Strategy and Tactics Conference, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Negro Question and the South - Research Materials, Clippings, 1940s, 1950s (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Negro Student Problems (Committee for the Conference), Undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Negro Work Commission, 1959 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Negro Work and Economic Status of the Negro Worker, Conference Material, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Negro Work for 1959 - Program Outline / Memorandum (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - New Foundations, Undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - The Niagara Movement, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - North, Joseph: Memorial, 1976-1977 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - La Nouvelle Revue Internationale(Published by the French Communist Party), 1978 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Nuclear Weapons, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Olympics, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - On the Loss of Eugene Dennis, Undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Ohio Victory Conference of Negro Youth, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Open Letter to the Golden Jubilee Convention of the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Patterson, William, 1957, 1963, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Patterson, William: Memorial Tribute, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Paul Robeson Symposium, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Petition to the United Nations on Behalf of 13 Million Oppressed Negro Citizens of the U.S.A., 1946 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - The People are Fighting Back Against McCarthysm, ca.1953 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - People's Daily World, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Political Affairs: Index to Articles Related to National Question / Black Liberation, 1949-1973 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Political Bureau (CPUSA) on Nuclear Energy (Meeting) / Materials by Victor Perlo, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Poll Tax, 1942, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Press Conferences by Jackson, 1955-1966 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Press Conferences by The Worker, 1962-1963, Undated (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Prestes, Lois Carlos (Brazil), 1964 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Rights Daily: Title of Proposed Daily Newspaper by Jack Redway, Nov 1963 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Robeson, Paul: Commemorations and Memorials, 1975-1991 (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Shields, Art, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Slave Trade, Undated (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Alexander, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 46)
  - South Africa, Undated (Box 15, Folder 47)
  - South African Congress of Trade Unions, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - South Vietnam National Front for Liberation Information Commission, 1969 (Box 15, Folder 49)
  - Southern Africa Project, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 50)
  - Southern Conference for Human Welfare, Undated (Box 15, Folder 51)
  - Southern Leaders Conference on Transportation and Non-Violent Integration, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 52)
  - Southern Newsletter, Undated (Box 15, Folder 53)
  - Southern Solidarity Bond, Undated (Box 15, Folder 54)
  - Southern Regional Council - The Negro Voter in the South, 1958 (Box 15, Folder 55)
  - Spain, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 56)
  - Spartacist League, U.S., 1984 (Box 15, Folder 57)
  - Speaking Engagements, 1 of 2, Undated (Box 15, Folder 58)
  - Speaking Engagements, 2 of 2, Undated (Box 15, Folder 58A)
  - Strong, Edward: Memorial, Undated (Box 15, Folder 59)
  - The Struggle Against White Chauvinism - A Study Guide, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Sudanese Communist Party Statement, Undated (Box 15, Folder 61)
  - Teaching: Class Outlines, Undated (Box 15, Folder 62)
  - Teaching: Course Schedules and Requirements, Undated (Box 15, Folder 63)
  - Teaching: On the History of Slavery, Undated (Box 15, Folder 64)
  - Teaching: Reading Lists, Undated (Box 15, Folder 65)
  - Teaching: Students' Evaluations of Jackson, Undated (Box 15, Folder 66)
  - Tenant Evictions, Undated (Box 15, Folder 67)
  - Time Line of U.S. History (African-Americans, Labor Movement, Radicalism), Undated (Box 15, Folder 68)
  - Today's Civil Rights Revolution - Address by A. Philip Randolph, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 69)
  - Third World Studies Program (TWSP) / All Staff Conference, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 70)
  - United Auto Workers Local 600, Undated (Box 15, Folder 71)
  - United Mine Workers, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 72)
  - United Tobacco Stemmers and Laborers Union Local 279 / Collective Labor Agreement, 1937, August 1948 (Box 15, Folder 73)
  - Vietnam, 1967-1970, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Vietnam Trip Notes, Undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Voices Against Apartheid and Racism, Undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Voting Rights: Alabama, Mississippi, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Weinstock, Louis, Undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - William Patterson Foundation (contains letters from Louise Patterson and Dorthy Burnham), 1963-1988 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Winston, Henry: Biographical, Medical, Petition for Clemency, 1959-1960 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Women's Committee for Equal Justice, Undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - The Worker, 1962-1967 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - World Conference for the Independent and Peaceful Reunification of Korea, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth, 1947-1952 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - World Federation of Democratic Youth / Pan-African Movement Conference, Address by Eldridge Cleaver, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - World Peace Council, 1977-1988 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - World Youth Congress, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Young Communist League, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Young Workers Liberation League, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Youth Education Outline, Undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Youth Affairs (National Conference), Undated (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Series XIV: Writings, Published.
  - Subseries XIV:A: Articles (In Chronological Order)
    - Bibliography of Published Writings, 1947-1992 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Articles Published in Foreign Languages, Undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Book Reviews, Undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - "The First Amendment or The Last Liberty" The Worker); "Where Negroes Live in U.S." ( Freedomways, Summer 1961); "Every 10th American..." ( Trooper Souvenir Edition Around the World, 1945), Undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - The Communist Position on Negro Question (New York: New Century Publishers, 1947) (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - "Struggle Against White Chauvinism" ( Advance - The Struggle for Negro Liberation, Michigan State Communist Party, 1949) (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - "Theoretical Aspects of the People's Struggle in the South" ( Political Affairs, August, 1950); "Forge Fighting Unity Against the Wall Street Workers and the Exploiters of the Southern Masses" ( Negro Work Commission Bulletin, Issue No. 1, 1950) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - The Effect of the War Economy on the South (Reprint, Political Affairs, Feb 1951) (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - "Mr. I.F. Stone and the Negro Question" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXI, No. 3);Notes on Recent Developments in the south" ("White Chauvinism and Negro Bourgeois Nationalism" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXI, No. 5), 1952 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - "The South Today, and Labor's Tasks" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXII, No. 10); The Southern People's Common Program for Democracy, Prosperity and Peac (Southern Regional Committee of the Communist Party, U.S.A., March 1953) (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - "Comrade Eugene Dennis: An Appreciation and An Amnesty Appeal" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXIII, No. 8); "Free Gene Dennis and All Political Prisoners!" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XXXII, No. 6), 1954 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - "For a Mass Policy in Negro Freedom's Cause" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXIV, No. 3), 1955 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - "For Full Economic, Political and Social Equality of the Negro People" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship), 1956 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - "The Challenge of Little Rock; Facing the 85th Congress" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No.1); "In Memoriam Edward E. Strong" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No. 5); "A Message to Party Organizations" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No. 1); "On the Struggle for Negro Freedom" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No. 3); "Rally to the Banner of Struggle for Negro Freedom - Key to Strengthening American Democracy (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No. 2); The South's New Challenge" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No. 12); The South's New Challenge (New Century Publishers, New York), 1957 (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "Basic Data on American Negro People ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVII, No. 10); "A Reply to Comrade Healey" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVII, No. 4); "The Rev. King's Outlook" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVII, No. 12), 1958 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - "Draft Resolution on the Negro Question in the United States" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVIII, No. 9); "The Negro Freedom Fight: Current Developments" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVIII. No. 1); "Some Aspects of the Negro Question in the United States" ( World Marxist Review, Vol. 2I. No. 7); "Who Threatens Our Country?" ( Mainstream, Vol. 12, No. 2), 1959 (Box 16, Folder 34)
    - "My Friend: Louis E. Burnham" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXIX, No. 6); "The Negro Question in the U.S.A." (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XXXVI, No. 2); To the First Party of the Americas ( Political Affairs, Vol. XXXIX, No. 9), 1960 (Box 16, Folder 35)
    - "Dr. DuBois Joins the Communist Party" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 12); The General Crisis of Capitalism Deepens ( World Marxist Review, Vol. 4, No. 1); "Towards Communism: The XXII Congress" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XL, No. 12), 1961 (Box 16, Folder 36)
    - "… And further on Negro History Week" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Freedomways, Winter 1962); "Culture in the Cause of Negro Freedom" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Freedomways, Spring 1962) (Box 16, Folder 37)
    - "The Democratic Uprising of the American Negroes" ( World Marxist Review, Vol. 6, No. 9); "A Fighting People Forging Unity" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLII, No. 8); "Harlem - a Community in Transition" ( Freedomways, Vol. 3, No. 3); "The Logic of a Noble Life" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLII, No. 10); "Negro Unity in America" ( New Times, No. 39); "Peace is Paramount" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLII, No. 12), 1963 (Box 16, Folder 38)
    - "Unity of World's Workers Must be Goal of Communists" (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; Information Bulletin), 1964 (Box 16, Folder 39)
    - "One Head Less" ( New Times, No. 45), 1965 (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - "Black Power" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLV, No. 9); "Class Confrontation in Freedom Struggle" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLV, No. 2); "The Communist Party of China and Internationalism" ( New Times, No. 40); "The Meaning of Black Power" ( New Times, No. 39), 1966 (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - "Behind the Changing Chinese and U.S. Attitudes" ( information bulletin, Vol. 93, No. 5); "Massacre at Newark" ( Freedomways, Third Quarter, 1967); "National Pride - Not Nationalism" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLVI, No. 5); "Negro Freedom - The Civil Right Movement" in Gus Hall Speaks For a Meaningful Alternative (annotation by James E. Jackson claims authorship; New Outlook Publishers: New York); "Party Must Be Example to Nation" ( Party Affairs, Autumn Quarter, 1967) (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - "Class Sources of Left Adventurism" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLVII, No. 2); New Program of the Communist Party U.S.A., Second draft (James E. Jackson co-author; published by CPUSA); "Vietnam: The Number One Front against Imperialism" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLVII, No. 7); "Socialist Working-Class Democracy" ( Political Affairs, Vol. XLVII, No. 9), 1968 (Box 16, Folder 43)